Register of the European Technical Advisers Records, 1918-1923
Hoover Institution Archives
- MISSION TO POLAND OFFICE FILES, 1918-1922
  - Coal
    - General
      - Telegrams (Folder 2-3)
    - Agreements with Germany (Folder 4)
    - Blockade (Folder 5)
    - Central European Coal Commission
      - General (Folder 6-7)
      - Brand, William S. (Folder 8)
      - Nutt, H.C. (Folder 9-10)
    - Coal Commission, Berlin (Reichskohlenkommissar) (Folder 11)
    - Coal Commission, Essen (Folder 12)
    - Consumption (Folder 13)
    - Conservation (Folder 14)
    - Export
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Austria (Folder 16)
    - Import
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 17)
      - Germany
        - General (Folder 18-21)
        - Teschen (Folder 22)
        - Upper Silesia (Folder 23-25)
    - Inter-Allied Coal Mission (A.C. Goodyear) (Folder 26)
    - Market (Folder 27)
    - Mines
      - General (Folder 28)
      - Dabrowa
        - General (Folder 29)
        - Names of mines and directors (Folder 30)
        - Red Cross relief (Folder 31)
      - Rada Zjazdu (coal mining company) (Folder 32)
      - Wage scale (Folder 33)
    - Prices (Box 45, Folder 1-3)
    - Production and distribution
      - General (Folder 4-7)
      - Europe (Folder 8)
      - Germany (Folder 9)
      - Poland (Folder 10-11)
    - Trade (Folder 12)
    - Transportation (Folder 13)
  - Coe, C.S. (Folder 14)
  - Commercial exchanges (Folder 15)
  - Concessions (Folder 16)
  - Cost of living (Folder 17)
  - Cruikshank, W.D. (Folder 18)
  - Czechoslovakia, Warsaw Legation (I.E. Behrman, Secretary) (Folder 19)
  - Czechoslovakia, troubles (Folder 20-21)
  - Danzig (Box 46)
    - General (Folder 1-2)
    - League of Nations (R. Haking, Commissioner) (Folder 3)
    - Port conditions (Folder 4-5)
    - Transportation of troops (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Durand, E.D. (Folder 2)
  - Economic conditions (Folder 3)
  - Electric works (Folder 4)
  - Equipment, purchase of (Folder 5-6)
  - Evacuation (Folder 7)
  - Explosives for Czechoslovakia (Folder 8)
  - Ferguson, R.N. (Folder 9-10)
  - Food
    - Control (Folder 11)
    - Fats and miscellaneous foods, imports from United States (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Food Export Corporation of America (Folder 2)
    - Food situation (Folder 3-4)
    - Grain
      - General. Reports (Folder 5)
      - Control (Folder 6)
      - Imports
        - General (Folder 7)
        - United States (Folder 8-9)
      - Marketing methods (Folder 10)
      - Romanian purchase (Folder 11)
      - United States Grain Corporation (Folder 12)
      - Wheat, world supply (Folder 13)
    - Livestock (Folder 14)
    - Potatoes (Folder 15)
    - Sugar (Folder 16)
  - Foreign commerce (Folder 17)
  - Furniture (Folder 18)
  - Germany
    - Border with Poland (Folder 19-20)
    - Economic relations (Folder 21)
    - Economic relations (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Employees in Poland (Folder 2)
    - Government
      - Finance Ministry (Behrendt) (Folder 3)
      - Foreign Ministry, Berlin (Auswartiges Amt) (Folder 4)
  - Gray and Company
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Torrey, Claire M. (Folder 6)
  - Haller, Joseph (Folder 7)
  - Hines, W.D. (Folder 8)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 9)
  - Hungary (Folder 10)
  - Hutchinson, Lincoln (European Technical Advisers, Czechoslovakia) (Folder 11)
  - Iron and steel industry (Folder 12)
  - Joint Distribution Committee (Folder 13)
  - Joy, Benjamin (Folder 14)
  - Karlinski, W.P. (Folder 15)
  - Kopec, Thadeusz (Folder 16)
  - Krasnodebski, J.P. (Folder 17)
  - Labor
    - General (Folder 18)
    - International Bureau of Labor (Folder 19)
    - Wages (Folder 20)
  - Landsberg, E. (Folder 21)
  - League of Nations (Folder 22)
  - Levre, Gaston (Folder 23)
  - Lithuania (Box 50)
    - General (Folder 1)
    - Vilna (Folder 2)
  - McCormick, Medill (Folder 3)
  - MacKenzie, Mrs. J.C. (Folder 4)
  - Majchrowicz, Thaddeus (Folder 5)
  - Marcussen, Max (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous. Primarily railroad material (Folder 7)
  - Mines. SEE ALSO: Coal/Mines
    - Explosives (Folder 8-10)
    - Machinery (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
    - Timber (Folder 3)
  - Navigation (Folder 4)
  - Oil
    - General
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Investigations (Folder 6)
    - Gasoline (Folder 7)
    - Vacuum Oil Company (Folder 8)
  - Peoples' Industrial Trading Corporation of the U.S.A. (Folder 9)
  - Pile drivers (Folder 10)
  - Poland
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Government
      - Ministries
        - General
          - Ministers' Council (Folder 12)
          - Paderewski, I.J., Prime Minister (Folder 13)
        - Agriculture and Public Works Ministry (Folder 14)
        - Appropriations Ministry (Folder 15)
        - Commerce and Industry Ministry
          - General (Folder 16-17)
          - Arct, Stanislaw (Box 52, Folder 1)
          - Doerman, A. (Folder 2)
          - Kramsztyk, G. (Folder 3)
          - Lempicki (Folder 4)
        - Finance Ministry (Folder 5)
        - Foreign Affairs Ministry (Folder 6)
        - Post and Telegraph Ministry (Folder 7)
        - Public Works Ministry (Folder 8)
        - Railways Ministry
          - General (Folder 9-14)
          - Bartel, K. (Folder 15)
          - Eberhardt, J. (Folder 16)
          - Wrobel, Ignace (Folder 17)
        - War Ministry (Folder 18)
      - Polish Consulate, New York (Folder 19)
      - Polish Consulate, Paris (Folder 20)
  - Polish American Society (Folder 21)
  - Polish-Danzig Convention (Folder 22)
  - Polish Foreign Trading Corporation (Folder 23)
  - Polish Purchasing Bureau, New York (Folder 24)
  - Polish Shipping League (Folder 25)
  - Polish State Loan Bank (Folder 26)
  - Posen (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Prisoners of war
    - Austria-Hungary (Folder 3)
    - Russia (Folder 4)
  - Red Cross
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Medical supplies (Folder 6)
  - Reparations Commission
    - General. Bulletins (Folder 7)
    - Ditmas, F.I.L. (Folder 8)
    - Falter, Albert (Polish Delegation, Berlin) (Folder 9-10)
    - Ferrero, Ernesto (Folder 11)
    - Isabelle, E.T. (Folder 12)
  - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 13)
  - Rodowicz, Stanislaw (Folder 14)
  - Rohn, Baron (Chief, Austrian Delegation of Goods Exchange for Warsaw) (Folder 15)
  - Romania (Folder 16)
  - Russia
    - General (Folder 18)
    - Ukraine (Folder 19)
  - Ryan, T.R. (Folder 20)
  - Ryan, W.B. (European Technical Advisers, Czechoslovakia) (Folder 21)
  - Salt mines (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Special orders (Folder 2)
  - Storage capacity (Folder 3)
  - Sullivan Company (Folder 4)
  - Tariff studies (Folder 5)
  - Textiles (Folder 6)
  - Timber
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Export (Folder 8)
  - Transportation
    - Barges (Folder 9)
    - Railroads
      - General
        - General (Folder 10-11)
        - Conferences (Folder 12)
        - Reports (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Statistics (Folder 2)
      - Allied Railway Mission
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Hammond, F.D. (Folder 4)
      - Cars
        - General
          - General (Folder 5)
          - Czechoslovakia (Folder 6)
          - Germany (Folder 7-8)
          - Hungary (Folder 9)
          - Upper Silesia (Folder 10-12)
        - Armistice cars (Folder 13)
        - Congestion, Oderberg (Folder 14)
        - Distribution (Folder 15)
        - Freight cars (Box 56, Folder 1)
        - Loadings (Folder 2)
        - Shops (Folder 3-4)
      - Czechoslovak Railway Ministry (I.E. Behrman) (Folder 5)
      - Electric trains (Folder 6)
      - Freight rates (Folder 7)
      - German Railway Ministry (Folder 8)
      - Liquidation (Folder 9)
      - Locomotives
        - General. Shops (Folder 10-11)
        - Austria (Folder 12)
        - Russian gauge (Folder 13)
      - Military (Folder 14)
      - New lines (Folder 15)
      - Oil trains (Folder 16-17)
      - Organization (Folder 18)
      - Organization (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Regulations and restrictions (Folder 2-3)
      - Revenue and expense (Folder 4)
      - Rolling stock
        - General
          - General (Folder 5-6)
          - Repatriation
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
            - 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Austro-Hungarian (Folder 2)
        - British (Folder 3-4)
        - German (Folder 5)
        - United States (Folder 6)
        - Vienna Conference (Folder 7)
      - Schedules (Folder 8)
      - Spare parts (Folder 9)
      - Supplies, delivery of (Folder 10-11)
      - Terminals
        - General (Folder 12)
        - Warsaw (Folder 13)
      - Ties (Folder 14)
      - Tonnage (Folder 15-16)
      - Traction
      - Traffic
        - General. Passenger (Folder 18-19)
        - Danzig and Vistula (Folder 20)
        - Poland, Austria, and Czechoslovakia (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
        - Polish corridor (Folder 3)
        - Romania (Folder 4)
      - Wawel trains (Folder 5)
    - Shipping (Folder 6-7)
    - Steamer advices and reports (Folder 8)
    - Steamer movements (Folder 9)
    - Waterways
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Vistula River, improvement of (Folder 11)
  - Typhus mission
    - General (Folder 12)
    - Gilchrist, H.L. (Folder 13)
  - Typewriters (Folder 14)
  - Upper Silesia
    - General
      - General (Folder 15)
      - General (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
      - Kesgycki, Daniel (Polish Consul General) (Folder 3)
    - Coal division after plebiscite (Folder 4)
    - Plebiscite (Box 61)
      - General
        - General (Folder 1-3)
        - Division plans (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Memorials (Folder 2)
        - Statistics (Folder 3-4)
      - Korfanty, W. (Polish Commissioner General of Plebiscite) (Folder 5)
  - White metal (Folder 6)
- MISSION TO THE KINGDOM OF THE SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES (YUGOSLAVIA) OFFICE FILES, 1919-1920
  - General (Box 63)
    - General. Conferences and materials related to closing the mission; also, special documents removed from files before storage (Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1920 Jan.-Feb. (Folder 3-4)
      - 1920 March-Sept. (Box 64, Folder 1-7)
    - Finances (Folder 8)
    - Maps (Folder 9)
    - Reports (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Automobiles and equipment (Folder 3)
  - Bridges (Folder 4)
  - Food trains for Austria (Folder 5)
  - Mines
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Bosnia (Folder 7)
    - Bosnia (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
    - Croatia (Folder 3)
    - Serbia (Folder 4)
    - Slovenia (Folder 5)
    - Vojvodina (Folder 6)
  - Railways
    - General. Correspondence, memoranda and reports related to specific projects (Folder 7)
    - General (Box 67, Folder 1-5)
    - General (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Belgrade direction (Folder 4-5)
      - Subotica direction (Folder 6)
      - Subotica direction (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Terminal improvements, recommendations (Folder 2)
  - United States War Department
    - Cancelled contract (Folder 3)
    - Surplus and scrap (Folder 4-5)